If you were looking at the order book, that's the best ask price, that's the, you know, the cheapest seller, there won't be that much liquidity behind it, and simultaneously in FX, this isn't all the liquidity in one goal, in one box, because we know it's fragment. You see? Because you can be trading on a ECN, but then there's another ECN and another ECN that has the own equity. There you'll get in the prices from the banks. The banks have the own equity, and it's all just a fragmented market, right? So the point here is,
If your manager told us to fill 50 billion,
you're not going to get it all in one clip.
What you have to do is you have to work your order into the market in pieces.
You're break into small pieces.
You're buying it through limit orders.
Wait for the market to hit you.
Or market ordering and taking liquidity from the market as well.
Right?
What's happened is to facilitate large buyers
or to facilitate liquidity finding and cheapen the execution cost,
we have entered the realm of automated execution algorithms.
the algorithms will you put it into the algal it will fill the order for you within your
parameters within your time frame and if it fails to fill it you know whatever didn't get filled
it just gets cancelled the algos do it I mean you've actually had a look at an example where
the liquidity follows prices higher and higher and higher yeah depending on how aggressive or
or time sensitive to trade is right yeah so these type of you know mechanisms that facilitate
trading that helps large, you know, volume coming and out of the market, because they're structured
and because they're parameterized, it results in quite consistent behaviors. Think about midflow.
Why does the base hold, you know, why does the last buy base in a bullish midflow continue to
hold is because there's liquidity accepting higher and higher prices. You get it.
Yeah. Are you following? Yeah, yeah, yeah. So I've got a quick look here. You know,
what's, you know, why is this one? Reaching back down and finding bids here, then building up,
and then runs, it dries off, runs down, the bids,
here, because there's a large order being filled over a, over a period of time. And simultaneously,
the available sell liquidity on the left is not enough to fill that single order in one go.
So the problem is large orders get filled in over time. And that consistently creates quite
reliable behaviors. Another example of another behavior is reliable. When the market's
become thin, there's a lack of liquidity on one side at least. And it's becoming more and more
expensive for that whoever's, you know,
pushing that move to trade because there's
not enough liquidity. Price is jumping over price
levels. Right? Whenever
the market becomes volatile, the willingness to
trade dissipates. It disperses.
Nobody wants to trade under
a volatile fast move because there's a lack
of liquidity in the market. So what
we continuously see is volume rises,
volatility rises because the dealers
they don't want to get hit, creates
the spike type movement and then as the
spike continues, the willingness to trade
it ultimately disperses and the volume dries off,
leaving behind, like we said, for years.
Yeah.
All right, that's why price draws looking to range.
And then we have also areas where orders rest.
So we had this thin shot down.
There was relatively thin trading.
And then back up here, there was a period of price stability
where market found value, and there was a lot of trade being facilitated.
When price draws back to these areas,
there's still willingness
to transact in that area there
and what happened down here
was just like a dislocation
as a result of like we said volume
market forces
someone filling a big order
by liquid
we disappear
etc etc etc
so we validated
why press basis is
and what it ultimately creates
is the price rate. It doesn't matter what time frame
it is it ultimately creates
price means. They're not all necessarily
the same
you know for example here you have a price swing up but it didn't feel right that price
swing got bit off the residual level and and continued and it continuously does that why because
that fractal swing is located inside of a larger series of buying okay so now we're going on to
like price swing sorry the liquidity principles that that apply to price so the further
price move, the weaker it gets, volatility to function available liquidity, et cetera, et cetera.
There's variable volume flow, meaning volume isn't coming in at the same size all the time,
which is the most, it's such an obvious example because, you know, there's, you know,
there's, let's say a million participants, they're not all buying at the same time.
They're not selling at the same time. It's actually, you know, going to be variable in the
intensity of how much volume comes in. Sometimes there's a lot of volume during the day when there's
a lot of business to be done. Then there's times overnight that there's not much volume.
and you know that kind of that kind of
dynamic exists
also every time price
becomes volatile nobody wants to trade
and again the volume dries off
okay
have variable volume float that further facilitates
why you see or further substantiates why you see
some of the price behaviour that we do
can you see trading for you
yeah yeah let me just open up
J4X
so
ultimately the whole purpose of all that was
to can give you
insight into why price behaves the way it does. And there's another principle is that sentiment
isn't a constant. So if people are net bearish, or if the whole, you know, the world is net
bearish, GDP, USD, it doesn't mean they're going to be selling every minute of every day.
Right? There'll be times where the selling dries off. There's a lack of sell liquidity in a way
and it takes very light to buying to push price against the sentiment trend. You know, so the trend
isn't a constant
what other
principles are there
I've even
even because you're the only
you're the last person
yeah so
it's price
seeks liquidity
basically price goes
to a less liquid side
extensions get filled
volatility is a function
available liquidity
we know liquidity
disappears when
well dealers pull liquidity
when they don't want to get hit
the further price
travels the weaker it gets
there's three sides
to a liquidity base
the top middle of the bottom
price is fractored
reason being because it's only
volume and so because it's only market orders
and limit orders that create the price
you know
regardless of what time frame you look at it on
price is going to be the same. The reason we can look at it on
one minute is because
whoever, you know, the general theme
or the general tradition is
to quote five decimal places
okay. Now imagine you could only quote
and dealers only quoted to two decimal
places. So you could only place orders at, you know, at the second decimal place only. You
can't place it lower than that. It wouldn't be a one minute chart. Yeah. Think about it. What
facilitates price discovery. What allows price to be made on a such a granular level is because
the fact that we can quote it at 8-4-4-4-4-1 and 2. Do you get it? Yeah. If you could only quote it
in the let's just say
at two less small places
there's that
there's 38 the bottom of it
yeah there wouldn't be a need for the one minute
it would be impossible to see what happened in the middle
because these are the only two prices that you can quote at
imagine that was the market
you know the rule in the market
where there's only two less more places
you call it a tick size
imagine one pip was 100 pips
yeah
there wouldn't be any prices on the
one minute because all it would be is just kind of spiking a hundred flips every time
every time you trade so that's an that's the reason why prices can be formed on the one
minute they're obviously much less less liquid reason being right now this is the
best available ask price right now that we can see in the market yeah from a collection
of dealers the you know so here we have five dealers one's quoting 38 38 30
392, 594, 38, 38, et cetera, et cetera.
Whoever's quoting the best, most expensive bid price that you can sell out is basically
buying at the most expensive price.
Nobody's going to be willing to buy it at the most expensive price a lot, if that makes
sense.
So although, you know, lower tick sizes or, you know, although decreasing tick sizes
and it cheapens our cost because we don't have to buy our 100 pips.
every time we can buy and sell in between
I can buy and sell in between you know for 0.00001
pips
whilst it helps us
cost that way
what ends up happening is there's much less
liquidity at the cheapest prices on these super
super you know granular levels
so the lower time frame has less liquidity
higher time frame is always going to have more liquidity
yeah working
in working order on a daily chart
you know
you know sorry
if we look at the daily chart,
sorry, that's just representing,
the daily candle just representing
where the market opened, closed,
and the high and the low of that day,
but over a course of 24 hours,
imagine how much volume transacts.
Yeah.
A whole bloody bunch of it, right?
So to simply move the higher time frame
for the daily chart to form two candles
that go up like this,
that means net on average
for 48 hours.
There was less sell liquidity than market order buying going on at that time for two whole days.
Imagine how much volume transacted over 48 hours just to push you up for two days.
There's going to be much, much more, if we look inside of it, concentrated pockets of liquidity, much more areas of balance.
And it's so much volume transacted over that time, there's going to be, if we look inside of it, you know, big, big pockets of liquidity left over.
So that's why the higher time frame pulls more liquidity.
It trades over a longer period of time, more volume transacts, more interest is in it.
So the higher time frame is reliable as more liquid.
Also another principle was obviously the market to limit order ratio.
You know what that is?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So when the market to limit ratio is below one, I think, yeah, yeah.
When it's below one, it's like a low liquid state, lower volatility.
buyers and sellers get matched.
So you're not on the wrong path.
So this is the best ask.
This is the best bid.
On the ask price,
there's four lots available
and on the bid price,
there's 10 lots available.
If you came in,
I came simultaneously at the same second
and I sold five and you bought five,
even though we're buying the same amount,
the price would go up.
right yeah because take five off there's still five left prices on anywhere take that four there's one
yeah it's going to move to the next one price goes up so um the market to limit order ratio here is
0.5 i bought five there's 10 there five divided by 10 is is 0.5 yeah but here you're buying five there's
only four there five divided by four is greater than one yeah the ratio so the market to limit order
ratio is an example, sorry, because of the way we trade through market and limit orders,
that's the market function. That creates quite a unique, I guess, environment where me and you
can be buying the same amount on the same second, but price still goes up. Really, you know,
me and you were buying and selling, we should just get matched and the price should go nowhere in
the real world. Yeah. So in the markets, it doesn't work like that. So like right there,
there was like more market buy orders than sell limit orders.
And, yeah, market to limit ratio was greater than one.
On the, on the, you know, upside.
Yeah. Because I sold five market order.
You bought five market order.
We're buying the exact same in market orders.
There's no disparity in our volume.
But because of the available liquidity being weak on that side, price went up.
And the same could be, you know, I could sell more than you just bought.
I could sell seven and you could still buy five.
And there's more sellers in this market than they are buyers
And still price goes up
So that's a super weird
You know, result of market dynamics
Think about it
How can they be more sellers and price goes up
Yeah
You know
So sorry, I've got a fucked up nose
Oh, you ill
Again, these are some of the principles that will
I'm not in, I've just got
Basically, I think I have an allergy to dust
Honestly, I think I'm an alligy to dust
I've had that person
since a young age
and I think
but dost makes it worse
Alhamda Allah I'm not ill yet
and then the next
principle was that price
reflects the state of liquidity
that is arguably
one of the most important principles
that you can understand
is because
price is a result of market
to the order ratio
and you know
yeah it's a result of the liquidity
make up the market to the motor ratio
so does price must always reflect
the state of liquidity right now
for the last five minutes
bread's gone up it's gone down it's gone up it's gone down you know you know what's going on
there's a balance between buys by liquidity and market order buying sorry sell liquidity and market
order buying and buy liquidity and market order selling there's a relative balance between them
probably because of low volume right there could be they could still be less liquidity here
they could only be one lot of liquidity there and five lots of liquidity there but not enough
volumes coming in to push it either way even though the sellers
a week.
Yeah.
So price reflects
the state of liquidity.
What that ultimately means
is whatever price does,
we can interpret it
to determine
what the current state
of the market is.
Is it in a liquid environment?
Is it a volatile environment?
Has, is the market balanced?
Is the market,
you know,
flowing in one,
is the one side of liquidity, basically,
and volume.
And as a result of,
you know,
as a result of,
sorry,
price will reflect each of those conditions
because that's what price will, you know,
if there's buy liquidity and there's a lack of sellers,
there's market order buying coming through
and prices mid-flowing higher,
from that we can determine that there is much
in a sell liquidity in a market, for example, right?
And if we continuously see that happening over and over again,
we get to directly, we're interpreting directly
what the state of the market is.
So price will always reflect state of liquidity.
The reason that's key is because the market environment changes.
can go from slow to fast.
And if we're tracking it, we can be the ones that spot those changes very, very quickly
because over time you've internalized the various characteristics of different environments,
of trending states, of balanced states, the type of levels that work on the inefficient
environments, the type of levels that work in efficient environments, what type of trading
you need to do.
So how long you can hold your trades, the frequency of your trades, the types of levels you can
use, et cetera, et cetera, all influenced by the state of liquidity that the market
it's in and we can directly interpret the state of liquidity simply through price that's a very
powerful powerful tracking price and then we eventually moved on to starting to exercise all right
so think about it this way we introduced concept then we went on to prices introducing the price
framework and then we started to finally talk about the dynamics of learning what your brain
needs to do to internalize all these various things and to eventually build a skill that's that's
refined enough, developed enough, good enough to trade these markets as they exist today,
to exploit those price behaviours we've talked about. And during that, I was saying what would
happen is it ultimately creates some psychological shifts and a change in your perception
of what it requires to trade markets. So for example, rather than looking out where price
is going to be in the next five days, we simply look at price as it exists right now.
we don't have to worry about the future
and what's going to happen
because we can observe it happening
in real time
right?
The counter actions to randomness
do you remember that?
Yeah, yeah, I remember that.
Were there if you don't want to ask?
If you don't remember, it's fine.
Oh, what was that last thing you said?
If you don't remember, it's fine,
but what are those countermeasures to randomness?
Oh, countermeasures to randomness.
To not know in the future.
No, because that's a bigger issue.
We're using price to trade
to find future movements.
but we can't tell the future
so how can we do it?
We know prices are consistent
and they behave in certain ways
but sometimes price changes
volatility and it can expand
and stop behaving in the right way
and desired way
how can we
you know
what are the measures that we put in place
to mitigate that risk
and mitigate the risk of trading
incorrectly or being wrong
too much etc
I think one was
tracking
like constantly tracking price
very closely
yeah tracking price very closely
that's one
the other one was
because we don't know the future
yeah
it's completely senseless
to make stringent
oh yeah yeah yeah
stringent expectations
of what's going to happen
what we should actually do
is consider multiple outcomes
because at any time
the market can just change
probably the environment
yeah
so one of the most powerful
things we can do
alongside tracking it closely is consider multiple outcomes.
What could price do?
Now, you know, if you took a random person off the street and you asked him,
tell me what price could do.
Give me a few scenarios.
The likelihood and the accuracy of his, you know,
possibility, possible outcomes would probably be, you know, not that good.
You get it.
Yeah.
Because he doesn't know how price behaves,
because probably he lacks a framework to contextualize price,
the likelihood of his expectations being that accurate is quite low.
Over time, you know, you kind of develop a relationship with price.
Based on the framework that we're applying, we can give price a location.
We can contextualize if it's volatile, if it's stable, and the various characteristics that exist.
By location, I mean, you know, is it an apex?
Is it in mid-flow?
There's a series of phases and stages that exist.
all of them are you know follow a relative path and based on that framework we can prime you know firstly give price a location okay so let's just say you observe a thousand apexes eventually you will have observed some apexes that fail so here's a low it fails and then eventually you will have experienced lows that are that that that work out because of both apexes
this is just a failed one and this is a good one and then also you will experience the variations of apixes right so you have apexes where you think you're up massively and then it comes all the way down just to just a fuck with you if you like that you have apexes which work through the shelf right it takes a while it works through the shelf you have apexes which retests the low but kind of miss it and then come all the way back down to the last bit of bias and then so the
There's variations, right? Over time, you have experienced all of them, and you will internalize
at least what is possible and what price could do at any given point during the development
of that particular apex. Do you understand? Because you've observed so many apexes,
tick for tick, at any given point, you could say to me, okay, this could happen right now,
because I've seen it in a past, this could happen, this should happen, this shouldn't happen,
etc etc so your ability to consider multiple outcomes based on where prices what is to win
the state of liquidity you will become much much more better much more comfortable with it but before you
reach that summit before you reach that summit you're going to make a lot of mistakes so there
be times where you know it comes all the way against your entry you cut the trade and it ends up
being the best trade in the day yeah there'll be times where it technically and it validates your
trade where you should have cut it, you hold
on to it, and
you know, you end up with a big loss.
And then there'll be times where
you, this is more
random, it's not your fault, there'll be times
where you cut the trade because it invalidated
and it ends up being in the way.
And this is just a less probable
outcome, but it still does happen at times.
It's less probable, but it still
happens at times. So
not only will there be you experience
in randomness that you can't control,
there will also be human error
because there's maybe, let's say, a lack of experience
and you're learning. So between you
reaching the pinnacle and being able to
consider multiple outcomes, regardless of what prices do,
and very accurately all the time,
and let's say
where you are currently on that path,
you have to have experienced all these
particular states many, many times and swings,
many, many times for your ability,
for your, you know, consider multiple outcomes ability
to develop. And then finally,
it's a probabilistic approach. Think about
what is much more likely. So if you've got,
a significant buy base on being picked up and significant weakness in the in the sellers
probabilistically you know that's like we're likely to see the apex hold as it exists right now
i wouldn't say there's a lot of sell equity in there so probabilistically you know we can expect any one
through there or even a response of there to be weak and eventually price to go through that high
just thinking relative probable terms rather than having stringent expectations of what price
yeah right one second yeah sorry about yeah no problem so um yeah consider multiple okay so
that is very relevant to exercising because now we're on that path of trying to experience prices
first of all the first step of exercising what was it first type of exercising
there was three steps of exercising right there was step one step two step three
do you remember what the first step was if you don't it's fine yeah no i don't remember that
bit. So it was to basically learn and build your ability just to simply see price swing features
and variations in prices. So I told you to go back, look over historical charts, build your
samples and mental memories as well of different types of swings. So we simply scroll back,
here's a big swing, you identify the show, you identify all the various features of it,
and subconsciously as well
when you're internalizing
that this didn't fill all the way down
okay so that might raise a question in your mind
you might ask me about that
and I would simply say to you
it's just one of those instances
it's not basically it's not guaranteed
to reach the call
and it's just much more likely
that we're going to get by as there
what that does then
is it gives you an answer to that question
I expected this to fill
I asked Sahel about it
why did it not feel he told me
that it doesn't have to fill it's more random
but what we do know is that
residual levels aren't that strong.
Over time, that allows you then question if what Sahel is saying is valid.
What you might think is, okay, Sully said it's going to reach the core, or that's where
the best buyers are, it didn't reach the core.
Maybe then there's a trade at residual levels.
Then you might try to start trading and exercising residual levels.
Over time, you will have an answer if residual levels have a positive expectancy or not.
but also what that does is it
but the substantiates that you're exposed
to randomness. Not every
going to feel. There'll be times
where the price behaviours, they're just
not that favourable at that time.
The way the distributing isn't favourably.
They're not the type of results you're looking for.
You know?
And that itself is a function
of you not know in the future
that they be in random
dynamic, random distribution of outcome,
they be in shifting states of probability,
that will then shape your view of the market
where you will stop thinking of definitive terms
you're much more loose with your opinions,
you adjust the way you look at the market
and that's one of the most primary obstacles
that any trader that wants to last in this business
needs to overcome the shift their perception
of what trading is.
You're exposed to randomness.
So there's a need time, are you exposed to not know in the future?
There's in me time, but you're completely wrong, bro.
You get it.
And once you become into with that, or eventually what it results in is, so imagine you continue to exercise and build this collection of, you know, experiences and reference points of price behaving and what they can do, what they shouldn't do, all this stuff.
And alongside that, you finally reach the conclusion that, yes, price might do the less probable thing.
It doesn't happen that often.
I just want the best setups that exist.
Yeah, definitely, yeah.
What you will eventually start doing is then stop taking the crap setups.
Stop the stuff that it causes you to lose,
like moving your stop and not cutting your trade
or holding onto your trade or whatever.
All that will matter to you as finding the best setups
because you then have shifted your perception
of what's required to trade.
You know, having counter solutions to randomness.
Having basically an edge.
There has to be an edge.
Why does your set a, is it random?
Are you just finding patterns in the market
and then trying to export those patterns.
You can do that with moving averages, you know.
You can do that with RSI.
But what will happen is either the volatility will change
and the RSI won't catch up
and you're going to have a period of losing
or basically that pattern will change in the market itself.
So I'll give you an example.
Before 2008, there used to be prop firms.
So small firms, let's say me and you, we've got their peers.
We open up a small office
and we hire prospective trade.
We give the traders, let's say, 50K, after some training, and then we say 50-50, 50-50 split.
If they make profit, we take 50%.
They're only allowed to lose the next percentage.
If they lose that much, they'll ever, et cetera.
So that's what prop firms are.
There used to be prop firms where man would sit looking at this ladder.
So they sell here, sell liquidity here, there's buy liquidity here.
And when news came out, they would listen to that news.
then after a million years later
click the buy button
and the price would move enough for them
to make profit after
so they would ladder trade news
but then as soon as algorithms came in
by the time it took for the trader
to observe the news digester
and make the decision to click the button
and then for his signal to get sent to the server
the algorithms already push the price
so far ahead that he's ended up buying up here now
he's been slipped but there's no liquidity
but his edge disappeared
his pattern that he observed disappeared
as the market evolved. He has no
edge anymore, one second ago.
So the point is, when you're
randomly observing patterns and you're
trying to build a system of it,
yeah, it'll work, but there's a risk that
your system
will stop working eventually.
Will you spot this very unlikely?
So I'm not saying, you know, people trading
moving averages, crossovers and all that, they're not making money.
They probably have found, you know, the best
environments to trade under, and which
moving average to use, depending on how
it's trendy or efficient
the marketes, etc. They can do that.
But also anyway,
with math-based models, it's lagging.
It's way too lagging. If volatility
changes, the moving average has
to, it itself, it hasn't
had enough data for its update and reflect
the new volatility.
So the moving average
is taking the closing prices of the last
50 candles, right?
The next candle pops,
that isn't a big enough pop
to change this moving average. It will only
spike or a tiny bit
you get it
yeah
so it's lagging so much
that
you know
the information is quite late
you really have to be
forward looking in the markets
as well
so we take a
probabilistic
anticipatory approach
trading the properties
price behaviors
are a result
of marking mechanisms
so that finally is not to
another point actually
is that we don't really care by
where the markets go
and you just kill by its behavior
you know if it's going from A to B
I don't care
I care how it's going to get there
What I don't want it to do is go on a straight line
Because then there's no opportunity from it
I don't chase
What I would love is for it to do this
Because then there's opportunity everywhere
Yeah
On both sides, yeah
On both sides
Et cetera etc
So ultimately we're trading the volatility
Which is a result of the market mechanics
Rather than
You know
Taking directional bets
Because in my opinion
And if you're saying that pound should be worth this much,
the likelihood of you are being right about what the true value of pound is from home,
I'll be honest with you, it's not that high compared to a quant firm who is mining
and is paying tens and tens of thousands of dollars to access data
to simply observe it and mine.
It builds models of analytical models to extract information about what the true value of something should be.
I'll give you an example.
there's one hedge fund
it's a quant
hedge fund
so a quantitative
computer based
hedge fund
they looked at
Walmart
and were wondering
what is next
earnings
figure would be
how much money
they earned
in that let's say
quarter
yeah
it did is
they pulled up
satellite images
of their carpox
and checked
how many cars
and how busy it was
that's just
an example
of the type of
information
and data they have
we can't
compare to their
models
you get it
you might be right
you know
I said
cables going to
150 it practically is near it yeah um you can be right about stuff like that but the only reason
i was right or kind of right it hasn't gone to 150 yeah the only reason i was you know kind of like
um likely to be right is because at this stage of the swing we've had a massive break of midflow
it's done a massive sideways and one of the biggest pops i've ever seen in my life naturally the
most natural and and a whole washed area that's a that's a that's a that's a break of midflow extension
That's a sideways pop.
Do you get it?
Yeah.
It looks like it's gone to that apex of that massive move down.
I think that high is weak, personally.
We might range here for a while.
But do not be surprised if Price starts to shoot out.
But also, don't be surprised that if we fill it all the way down here.
Yeah.
It's just a weird one right now.
I'm short from one.
I'll show you what I'm short from.
I can pull it on.
also let me know where you need to go yeah
I don't want to do you too
yeah yeah as soon as it broke
Daily Shelf
I thought yeah this could
retest it
yeah and then start moving down a bit
but I mean weekly is already
like still midflow
pretty aggressive midflow
that's a brilliant point
well actually should do
what I am gonna do is explain what price
are doing and hopefully you can have your own
you know you have your own observation
so it broke daily shelf
and you thought what
yeah I thought it could
it could have gone higher
like to know like the
the apex of it of the daily
go deeper into it yeah yeah yeah yeah but obviously
you just went to there but um weekly
so i am short i am short from
142-004
that trade is currently up
how many pips
that trade is currently of 250 pips or something
300 something something which yeah
um i've only got 80k left on that
on that size, the lot size.
So 0.8 lots.
I closed most to be probably in that first day.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm not a swing trade, you know?
What we try to do is, eventually, is catch our trade, yeah?
So let's say you've got a good response and take our money, basically.
Yeah.
We're trading the volatility.
So price spikes up.
We short it.
It moves enough three, four, four, five, or intradate, take my money.
I don't care.
I'm here to make money.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Sometimes, sometimes,
price is in the right
location.
So here, all through here, there was not
any sell liquidity. There was
no real sell liquidity. It's quite obvious
it's going to have to become more inefficient
than that extent, yeah?
So if I was taking shorts here,
there was no way I'm looking for a runner. But when
it finally hit the core
and it became super, super inefficient,
there was much more of a scope
and probability of having
a bigger trade. So, in
In those instances, what I'll do is I'll take my trade, take my money like I normally would, leave a piece on, leave a small size on for a runner.
The same with WTI.
I'm long from $5.
$5?
Oh, you've had it on since like months and months, haven't you?
Months, bro.
I think still when you had Twitter.
Yeah, when I had 12.
I even said the day before I'm buying.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
but I've only got 50 barrels on
0.5 lots
I haven't got my full size on
it's absolutely mental to think
that I would sit there for 12 months
and not full size on
no one's doing that
because they're fulls
unless you're a fund
you know
yeah
you know like
there will be
speculative funds
yeah
that takes specialty positions
and there will also be
segments of investment banks
that have a view
of where oil should be
so they will themselves
raise infantry of oil they've kind of they will be longer and longer
build a bigger position yeah a segment of the invest number but me as a day trader
not that's fine you know just completely against what I do on a day to day it's
very hard for me to hold on to full size after four or five all yeah very difficult
yeah you just I just want to take your money and just it's my money man it's my
money bro okay you get it yeah exactly my money and also uh let's just say you're looking for
a 10-R trade for you to get that 10-R trade you will have probably have had three or four
trades that hit three R four or five R and went back on you and you had to cut and then finally
that that fifth or six trade goes to 10 R yeah if this if you added all that oh they'd be more
than 10 R anyway and then you would have took four or here you're up more do you get it
but when you're looking for runners you're going to have more trades that fail and then when
you are looking to trade my way where you take your money you're going there's going to be that
one trade you close and that that will be the trade that would have run a thousand yeah you get it
but that doesn't mean like the next time you do it that it's going to be 10 off again say again
say again sorry yeah i was i was just saying that obviously if you've seen that last one go 10 r and
then you're like oh you know what the next one i'm just going to keep it on and see what happens but
then it doesn't do exactly exactly like you don't know the future you know so
So if you decide to be that trader that wants to look for the bigger ones, you find it more comfortable and it's just more suited to your personal, you know, psychology and risk profile, what you will eventually realize is that a vast majority of your trades that you take are not runners and you have to be much more patient, right?
But if you want to be more active and trade prices very actively, you'll realize that basically you're going to miss a few runners, right?
but then there's
so that's a fact of trading short term
or slightly longer
but then there's also times where
prices in the right location
and you have a you have a
you know I guess what do you call it
a sixth sense that
based on the location of the price swing
based on the levels
and what's happening on the higher time frame
when I say location of the price swing
I mean the higher time frame location
where there's a greater probability
of a bigger run then maybe then you will
keep a bit of a size on
You won't hold your full size because unless you're obese,
unless you're a madman that can do that stuff,
you will likely take your profit, leave a bit on, let it ride,
and then just forget about it.
So I did that with oil.
I'm long at $5.
These prices are, they're not the same on CFDs, yeah?
So all CFD providers have different prices
because the broker is connected to the prime broker,
and the prime broker is connected to the exchange.
that oil is trading on.
Yeah, I remember, I think I saw a couple of them
and they went into minuses, yeah.
So what happened is the real,
so this is not the real oil price, right?
The real oil contract, what's it called?
The real oil contract, WTI,
it trades on Nimex,
which is an American exchange.
I don't even think it's called crude, you know.
I don't think it's called,
thing you know with WTI is called crude yeah so this is the current contract of of the real
oil barrels this is the real price of it for you to get that price or for you to trade the real
price of oil you have to be connected to the exchange you have to set at the table or at least
have a clear you know have a broker who can you can trade you can pass the trade on to the
exchange for you but what our brokers do is because it costs to set out that seat
they get their prime broker
who's already connected
to the exchange
to take that price
they can't copy that price
exactly because the prime broker
will have to pay
for a different feed
what they do is
they change the price slightly
so if crude oil here
is quoted at 6111
look at the price here
at 6109
you get it
so they change the price
slightly so they don't have to pay
fees to the exchange
that's why CFD provided
will have all different prices
and when the contract went negative
all the CFD providers stop quoting it
they just stopped about we're not trading this today
where with this
where I bought it here that says 10
on the real crude contract
on the CFD I bought it at 5
it was a completely different price
you get it
is because they're all quoting
the change of the prices
so they don't have to pay fees to that to the exchange
so cool
um
how did I get on to this
we're talking about exercising
yeah
talking about perception shift
GU
yeah yeah yeah cool
exercise in step one
was introducing
you see the price swing framework
but not introducing you sorry
getting you used to seeing price
swings
and and how consistent they are
your ability to spot price swing features
um
yeah just to be able to see that
that stuff in price quite accurately
Because we know not all priceings are the same.
Some are more subtle, some more vague, and others are more clear.
You need to be able to see all of them, regardless of what prices.
That should be the lens through which you try to view or interact with price through.
Some people, they try to draw an average or try to draw a trend line.
What we do is we contextualize the current state, the location of the price swing stage
and whether it's efficient and efficient, how fast it's moving.
But that then involves time frame.
so what you can have
one of the principles was that
the higher time frame governs lower time frame
as well right
yeah
so the lower timeframes are the building blocks
of the higher time frame
so if the higher time frame
is in a bullish mid-flow
and it's relatively efficient
what we then know is the fractal swings
inside of that should
not really be filling back down to core
meaning we have a run
if the higher time frame
is seeing liquidity except higher and higher prices
it makes absolute sense
for this fractal one to not fit
if it filled
it wouldn't be
a relatively inefficient
it would be
highly efficient
or that makes sense
yeah yeah that makes sense
yeah
yeah so
time frame is a key key
element
in actually trading it
you know
using price swings
in live time
in real time
because the high time frame
will govern the lower time frame
the fractal swings you see are making up
and the building blocks of the higher time frame state
and that adds a level of complexity
you have to get used to viewing the lower time frame
relative to the higher time frame
right
that does add a level of complexity
you need experience to do that
so you can see price swing and now you're in step one
the next step is
applying the price swing to live prices
using that
to anticipate what price
might do next what it should do what it shouldn't do and before you can actually do
that quite accurately you simply need to be able to track price and give it context
you get it so historical prices have already happened this swing's already done
they don't need to do anything or then identify character features of it you know
swing inefficient but right now what we've had is a bullish made flow
possibly a side of his part a clear break of shelf
Yeah, are you with me?
Yeah, yeah, I'm here, yeah.
Yeah, so a clear breaker shelf.
If I asked you to follow this now as it unfolds and tell me what price is doing,
it may become more difficult.
You might set an expectation that price, you know, it broke shelf, it should sell off,
or end of capital and it goes against you.
And it goes all the way to the top.
And then the few, you know.
So ultimately, we start applying the price swing,
phases to start
anticipating what price should be doing
but you're not
going to be able to do that accurately
so we're going to do that.
Step two of exercising
has three sub-steps to it
if that makes sense.
So step one,
build a sample set
of price swing features.
Yeah?
Build a sample set
and be able to see them.
Step two is starting to use
the price swings
to navigate price,
to track price,
to anticipate what's going to happen next.
and doing that is basically
basically difficult
so what we do is we
split step two into three pieces
just identify and explain
what price is doing is step one
so don't think about where it's going next
simply identify all the information you can
so sideways pop let's say
it's not definitive it could fail
but at the moment it's the most inefficient poppy pad
yeah there's a shelf
identify what these levels are
identify where the core is
identify then what price is doing
this is a relatively efficient shot
and naturally
whilst you're doing this you're going to want to predict
what's going to happen next you're going to want to do it
and that's good but just know that
it will often not fit your
expectation and what
that does is you being wrong about
what price you do what that does is
it again creates
a level of adversity
or like
discomfort where you then have to change
the way you look at price. Rather than forming strict expectations, you now know that you could
do multiple things. So you're okay, you know, you're much more okay with not knowing what's going
you know, you're much more okay with various different outcomes. Yeah, I'm short here. I don't expect
to sell off straight. Let's say, I'm not sure there. I'm saying, let's say I'm short there.
I'm not expecting it to sell off straight. Me personally, I know there's a wide variety of things
that can happen and I'm comfortable with that. Whereas someone that's less experienced would have much
more stringent expectations
yeah this has to sell off
or I'll give you an example
have a boy
he is a property developer in London
and when I tell you he has the best look
that I've ever come across
if bro if he said
you know that pound's going to hit two dollars
I bet you it would probably end up paying two dollars
telling you this guy
whatever he says turns to gold
yeah so I listen to
like like if he says
I think this will happen I listen to him
but what because he's not a trader
because he's not a trader
what he wants is
for his entry to go up immediately
or
let's say
because I got him in at 7 cents
no that's 1
QSP
I got him into this trade at 7 cents
down here
no that's one
that's one that's one
where's yes
what the hell would do
okay so we were in this possible
apex this is like last week
on the 16
in this possible apex, right?
It could have sold off.
I know that everything's in a speculative bubble,
that these apexes are just low volume.
Ultimately, everything's going up.
We're in a speculative bubble.
There's one limited dollars in the world looking for returns.
Safe bets.
So like safe assets are not returning anything.
So people are willing to take risk.
So they invest in companies and now cryptos and do you get it?
Within asset bubble, the most unique environment
that you're going to get compared to FX.
FX is not showing any asset bubbles, right?
It's showing some dollar weakness,
but it's not showing like a bubble
where something spiking and going up and up forever.
Because as we previously explained,
FX is not necessarily an asset class.
It's more a conduit to access different asset classes.
It's a channel.
So if I want to go from American assets to French assets,
the channel I take is do FX.
Yes.
You get it?
And the participants of FX,
they're not all trying to make money
and speculate and make directional bets.
There's a wide variety of participants.
So FX ultimately isn't going to behave like a risk asset.
When everyone's feeling risky, risk assets go and speculative bubbles.
And when that happens, you ultimately have a narrative where price goes up,
people give it a reason.
That confirms why price went to opt so they buy more.
Price goes up further.
That further substantiates their reason.
So price continues to go on.
And any, any narrative, any narrative catches on.
Yeah.
I'm telling you, any narrative patches on.
And now think about these smaller coins, which don't have that much liquidity in them.
And then these groups of people find a narrative because someone, you know,
whoever owns that coin, put a research paper out.
He sounds sick.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Or someone that's prominent in the crypto community backs that coin.
They're not a lot of liquidity in it.
It's quite easy to push prices off.
You get it?
Yeah.
So the point is, an asset bubble, a speculative asset bubble, will not behave like what you're expecting in pound.
So this guy, he was like, yeah, I want to buy it here at 8-2 that day.
Yeah, I was like, just wait.
There's a wash level here.
They're flipping level at 7-4.
Put a limit in at 7-4 and just wait for it.
He wasn't willing to wait.
He bought at 8-2.
Price spiked to 7-4, pick me up.
And then price flips the shelf.
The shelf flipped and he was like, oh, bro, shall I cut it?
Shall I cut it?
Should I cut it?
Because that moved down.
And then he was like, oh, bro, and it's going to go back up.
They went back up and it's come back down.
What's happening?
You get it.
Every tick against him, he was worried because what he wants is, as an inexperienced person,
but he wants price to go straight up.
I know that it won't go straight up.
It's a very big volume flow.
Yeah.
So over time, I've built in and changed my perception of how price will unfold.
I don't care how it unfolds.
I'm just tracking to see if it's favourable and favourable.
Has it changed?
Is it a good time to cut?
Is it weak to do that?
Yeah.
So setting reasonable expectations, you will try to do it.
You will most likely be wrong some of the time.
And then that will force you to consider variable, variable outcome.
So the step 2.1 or 2A, let's call it, is to simply explain what prices do.
tracking and explaining tracking and explain it so if we go here right now and then there's a level of depth
that you can take it to extremely detailed depth where you explain what price did from the weekly
to the daily all the way down to what it's doing right now or you can simply just get used to
tracking it on the one minute yeah yeah and then what will happen is have a state like this on
the one minute and the level it worked yeah that level it worked that will happen and then
you know uh sorry so it will look like the price behaviors are working then because we're not looking
at the higher time frame price will spike and these levels will stop working and you will question
why did that not work we look on a high time frame and the high time frame state shifted and that
will then give importance to considering what the high time frame status yeah you will come to me
and ask oh why they do that i will tell you use the high time frame and then you will start contextualizing
the higher time frame adding a bit of complexity to learning but it's something again that
you have to overcome.
So you're at step 2A or 2.1 right now.
What we'll do for the rest of the session
is try to find a point or something that's moving
and just track it together.
You're on step 2.1.
Step 2.2 will be contextualizing using the higher time for them
and then using price swing
to anticipate what's happening next.
Yeah?
Yeah.
And then step 2.3
is looking for
the sponsor basically
the response that you think will work
whereas in step 2.2
you're considering what will happen next
but not looking for trade
you're just considering
it will extend it, you won't extend
this level should we respond
but then at step 2.3
you're actually looking for responses
and then step 3 is
finally comment up
with some form of
let's say steps or observations
about how to trade this environment
or that set-up or which-and-set-up is good.
So how to trade an efficient environment,
the characteristics of that, the types of level of that work.
How to trade other environments that are less efficient
and the level of that work there, and etc.
Step three is probably for you a while out.
You get it?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
This exercising process should continue
for the rest of your trading career,
regardless of how much money you're making.
For me to get tomorrow and I wake up
and trade this one day,
I've had two days off on the weekend.
I don't really practice in the weekend anymore.
What I need to do to get back in my group
is simply just to start tracking it a bit.
So I'll track it, I'll draw levels,
I'll see how it's responding.
And that will remind me of a few details.
It will remind me, okay,
you need to care about this information.
You need to care about when price misses level.
This is an observation now.
When price misses your level, you know, you want to go short here, you want to go short here, but price missed it, I know not to chase that level on.
And often it will end up spiking to it.
So I'll stay patient.
That will be a reminder of that.
Did you get it?
Whereas if I didn't remind myself of that, probably I might take an apex re-test and I would have failed.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
So small reminders and observations that you've drawn over the time, over time, you're not going to remember them all at one point.
It reminds you.
So to get back in my groove and to get back in sync with price,
I track it and I exercise with the start of the week.
I start every day once, anyway.
And throughout the day as well, when I'm bored.
So that's cool.
Anyway, let's get into it.
So before I do that, I will look at what cable did and explain my ideas.
Bro, your mic's gone a bit, does you?
Can you hear me?
Yeah, yeah, that's better.
You see J. Fretter?
Yeah.
So here's my lower time from chart, local pay.
which means what price is doing right now then you have your higher
sorry there should be there then you have your levels chart so obviously
price hit a level from 2018 to go and find those levels and sometimes
i need to go into these levels so i'll go back i have a separate chart for this level here
just to identify them and then i'll also go back on this chart as well draw them on
but i won't have to scroll back to see them levels again i can simply just get them
yeah yeah then i have my higher time from chart which is h1
H4, 4 daily, and then I have my higher, higher time frame chart, which is my weekly.
The reason I have a higher, higher, higher, higher time thing chart is because what I don't want
is on my H1 to have a weekly shelf on me that stretches, and just a big black box.
So I have it here, you can see it.
As soon as I cross down to my one hour, you cannot see it down there because I'm hidden.
And really, it shouldn't even be on this on this chart.
I made this higher, high, high time thing chart in here.
So on the higher high time frame chart, what I have is like big levels.
The H1 chart is quite an important chart and local player chart is where I'm tracking price today.
And the levels is obviously so good job.
So we know we had a weekly shelf here.
Yeah.
And we had a kind of missed the BA, at the top of the BA.
Yeah, that's September though.
Strip the shelf.
So we had a price run down.
flip the shelf, went into bullish mid-flow,
extremely efficient.
Some of the best trading environments out of that,
some of the best trades I've taken,
you know,
basically it's just been a super nice amount.
Yeah?
And then price started to accelerate higher.
That itself was anticipated.
I can show you a picture where I caught this low.
I didn't hold it all the way up.
But price became more inefficient.
I just did, didn't really trade too much during that phase,
caught the short, and again, it's relatively efficient again.
You should probably spite for it.
at least down to about
130-something
but ultimately
we were highly highly efficient
we broke shelf here
for the first time
we continued staying efficient
no real sell liquidity on the left
so it was always
you know in my mind that we will
accelerate or fire it
we had to do it had to do
the level it is this
so we have the big shelf
yeah yeah
then you have the shelf of this
run yeah and this is the the fractal that we retested that shell on the way down this level
responded as well I think all every level here I'm sure it responds we go back I'm sure
that level responded man yeah yeah yeah so we we had like a 30 30 20 bit move off that level
right and price actually went to the top side I'm sure there's a feed a day if we go back
more rich.
So the way price was moving at that point,
you wouldn't really be looking to short it
because it's broadly efficient.
Yeah.
You know, weighting to something
to spike in like that.
And I caught this retested.
14204, which is that.
Yeah?
Yeah.
In the morning as well.
So, yeah,
cable was higher time from efficient.
You could trade in any direction.
You know, levels are working on the left.
Even though there wasn't too many great level in there,
we're working price shifted and became an efficient let's have a look at what that looks so
here we're starting you know here we're seeing really deep pullbacks and long periods of swings
filling and filling them filling back to core that's back to core this one obviously yeah that's back
to core and then almost always back to core yeah and then look at it's guess above shell runs
fills, that's a shell free test
runs, doesn't fill
that's your first sign of
price not becoming
or price becoming
mission actually
it runs
the scope for it's taken up a shot high
and fill
and then these fractal ones
got to start doing that shit
and then it accelerates
that's that's 2 a.m.
overnight does nothing
spikes beneath Asia range
continues
continue
here it became
evident when it started to continue that the price it should be you get it yeah here is where
i would have a sign that's that's that's the end of a day this is the next day after like two
days um here let's say i took a short it didn't feel i i get stopped at break even because
my high becomes the invalidation i take another short overnight doesn't work despite beneath
asia range ends up running for the rest of the day they are their common characteristics of
inefficient higher time right yeah they're not feeling anymore already
back down all day exactly yeah so i can catch on to a shift very very quickly but
the phase where i would have hoped that price stayed efficient and for it to fill down so i might
assured that i might assured that i talked too lost cool but then i would have got scabs here the
extension beneath the age low and then continuing the trend is a very common characteristic
and higher time frame in efficiency so when price becomes in efficient
so yeah
that's what cable's
really done
and then you saw
that last pop on the H1 end of there right
yeah
that is what I would call
a flash spike
that
that's like a flash crash
but a flash spike
there's no way
you're getting short here
if you were short here
actually enough
you would have been alright
if you were short here
you would have got filled on your stop
but if you shorted it here
you were down
yeah that's probably
a count gone
if you're over leveraged
your stop loss
would have got
slipped 100%
and all of them
so
luckily though
that was at 1 a year
but I'm not trading
luckily
there would have been
a very high likelihood
and I would have tried
shorten this at a level
and I would have got
completely run over
and took like
when my stop loss
was one hour
they would have got slipped
like three four
five or
you know
that would have pissed me
so you get looking
like that as well
and because it's overnight
it's less
the couldy volume dries off we had a shot of volume i don't know why we had a shot of volume but um there was
lack of the putty in the market and price just spiked yeah that's some weird time for it to do that
also during this shift that we had here price became inefficient isn't filling the runs
we have these fractal runs though that have their own shelves that's not the shelf of the higher
so that's not a break um we look at the h4 becomes more evident actually you know what is a
break of this run here by this always buy days by days by days by days that's the first break runs
that's another break actually it's not it's not because this is a daily run these are h4 runs
they have their own shelves cool the shelf would have been back on the daily okay uh it continues
and it starts so we have a h4 run down it
apex and another H4 run up
and that itself leaves
behind and it starts to become much, much more
inefficient than these ones are much more
directionally driven at least, not relatively
pop stop, pop stop,
runs, doesn't break them that
much and then here shoots
continues, continues
and actually is driving
higher until the pop but that
broke midflow multiple times
that broke midflow here
technically
there, washed
break and then the surge
it's almost
need
at least fill it back down to shelf
which is that
you get
yeah
so in cases like that
go ahead
in cases like that
you really have to
look at the higher time frame
and
bear the prices
yeah
what matters is the higher time frame
stake because it governs
the lower time frame prices
what that means is
if the higher time frame state
is inefficient
and the candles are like this
the lower time frame fractal swings are also
basically the blocks of it
they're the bricks of it so they are not going to be filling down
and filling and you know
and flying by liquidity and low prices
they're just going to continue to hold
and hold and hold you get it
in this environment
you have to be very weary of taking shorts
and not trying to hold on to them
we can take short just not hold on to them
because you know these fractal swings
might move down 30 pips and it's high time
inefficient but the point here is
ultimately the high time frame is the most
important for your trading because it will influence what type of trade you take. High time
friends efficient here, well if you close your eyes on the long term, even if you remove to
your stop plus, it will come back into coffee for you, all that shit. It's forgiving it. It's lovely.
Then the environment changes. If you don't spot the change, you mess up. So that is another
thing that you will experience. But then also how to trade this environment. What's the best
level? What should I do? Should I trade these extensions? Should I hold these extensions short?
should i what level should i use on the left i have multiple levels to use which one should i
use yeah and it ultimately ends up going to this level i think one 142 39 142 no's perfect
41 yeah so it goes to uh this one this level you get it yeah so um it's a practice
LePEC, here is a daily shop I think, this is this show.
Yeah?
No, we'll talk about it.
Sorry.
This is that shelf hit.
You can have a look at it.
Yeah?
You see?
This is the level of price hit.
Back to Lapex.
Retested the daily shelf.
And that's the level that I ultimately need.
That is a quite a responsive level by the day.
The level that retests the shelf and shifts lower is often responsibly.
I didn't take the high, you know, I wasn't away, but when I woke up and I saw it hit that level.
And we had that massive surge with so much weakness.
It was almost inevitable that price goes to a day shelf, which is, if you look at it,
yes, there's pockets here, but that's a factor wrong.
That you treat that individually.
That has its own shelf.
which you will see here.
So now I'm introducing to the complexity of
given price swings a location,
how they fit into the higher time frame context,
there's various high time frame states,
the location of the higher time frame swing,
if I told you that this is where cable is
on the daily chart right here,
what would, you know,
if I give you access to the paint,
what would you be looking to do
first of all this is a higher time
thing this is day
yeah
so what I want you to do is try and explain to me
what may happen
etc from here
okay
you should be able to draw
what your thoughts are
okay so
yeah so if this is a day's shelf
so it's invalidated it there
it's picked up
something residual there that's also residual but then it's like proper extended through
it I mean I think it could probably do this then go back okay so how would you
time that trade let's see you want to time that trick can you do it on a daily but
if you if you went to them a daily no no no your stop plus goes past the low that's a
3040 50 pimps yeah no it wouldn't be anything off the daily so what could we do
Go down to the timeframes and check this fractal swing from here to here.
Okay, my man, perfect.
So what you've done is you've identified a location on a higher time frame
which may end up causing a huge shift.
And to tantalrate, you're using the factor concept,
that this individual run lower is located at a daily shell,
possible B.A. retest.
You understand?
Yeah.
You're giving it a location.
That location is a brilliant location to be long.
Now what you're doing is you're observing this factual swing for weaknesses, the sideways,
the park into a level and increasing your chances of not only an immediate response
where you have a manageable response, but now you're also in a position where there's a likelihood
that price will run deep, deeply higher on higher time thing, where you'll get your swing trade.
Now finally, imagine if we were here on a daily chart.
yeah yeah and price did this what um what would you be thinking here or what's possible so
or at least explain what's going on and then i'll be okay so what this looks like it looks like
it looks like a pretty aggressive midflow how it's relatively yeah pretty aggressive with
it's daily you don't think of a week just getting bit up and not feeling yeah that's not filled that's not
filled that's not filled that's not filled um so uh let me just write this out i'm thinking honestly
anything that comes to mind there's not much you can be wrong about anything that comes to mind yeah
yeah so there's a few possibilities right extension past high well feel moves higher
and that's what is possible yeah yeah cool so first of all what it would make sense to do is
observe the level of that price
is hitting on the left
which is basically
okay okay
yeah
observe what levels
likely than be weak levels
but that's just
one of thinking naturally
but what the most important
thing to do here is
contextual as you just said to me
is quite aggressive
what that means
is to be an accepted
that higher and higher
advice
right
and because these levels are weak
and through experience
what you'll realize
this run is
much more likely
probably
probabilistically sorry
not guaranteed
probabilistically to actually accelerate okay you get it there's a likelihood that this is
going to accelerate so we were slow slow slow slow and then accelerate we were we were
slow slow slow and then get it yeah ridiculously accelerated and even these these fractal ones
slow slow slow slow accelerate yeah so this is you know you're going to observe it happen and
run over them the next time here you naturally immediately you will think there's a risk
to be accelerated so I don't want to hold on to any shorts yeah you can definitely short it
but I don't want to hold on to any shorts yeah because it's daily uh like if it was one minute
if you know nobody cares yeah because you're not going to try to short this with three
pips you're actually going to wait for it to pop and then short it hopefully filling the whole
one yeah yeah but it's daily it lasted weeks and weeks and weeks now what you would have initially
do is look at this fractal run we would contextualize it that this is a fractal run let's say
15 h1 yeah located in a higher time for embellishment flow which is broadly broadly uh uh it's
not efficient it's broadly stable but it's relatively inefficient because it's leaving these
big holes behind yeah and
So you contextualize it
It's the continuation factor one pushing to the highs
What it would make sense to do immediately is
Is that one
So here we're looking at it yeah
H1 sorry you H1
We're looking at it as running
It's drifting small pullbacks
And now we get a bit of a break of middle flow
It's H1
So you know
He's running higher, broke mid flow
What level here is on the left
That price might respond to
Is it a residual level
It's a residual? Is it a factual call
that's residual is it a core
is it a daily
level that this
fractal level is located inside it
etc etc right
and then based on that
if price then start to surge
this is H1
I would further break
this one down and look at it and
you know look at how it's running
on the 5s and the 15s and the ones
and then when that also becomes an efficient
into a level
there's going to be my timing of an entry
but I know this entry that I took in a one minute
it's located inside
the H1 run
which is located inside
of a daily
broadly inefficient run
that may become more inefficient
I'm not looking to hold short
for you get it
I'm looking at
to fill this extension
which is of probably 30, 40 pips
and take my money
and run
which would
simply translate
on the daily chart
let's just say that was the end of the day
yeah
when that took that short
and afield
which is likely to be the case in trends,
or translate into a small dip.
And hopefully we can get a sideways for a few days
and price is nothing, and then we can trade up and down on.
So I'm just giving you insight into what you will eventually have to do
to trade well, is give a context to price,
not only what rare prices in this run,
but on this factor one, which is up,
and itself has multiple factors, but here's one big one,
where that is located
and the implication of that
and your experience of the trading
and what's possible
think about the amount
of possible variations
and different contextual
states that price can be
and you know
we have to get doing this job
quite intensely
you know just you observe me
so you're at step 2.1
I'll let you go in about
two minutes
yeah no point
you're at step 2.1
all I want you to do is on the ones
and the fives and the 15 years
draw your levels
wherever you think is liquidy
if it's washed give it a washed
a washed column
and then
explain what prices
and obviously here's your shelf
and draw your price
from the stage
you know what price from the stage
you're saying
ask them if you don't know
explain that this is an extension
verbalise it in your mind
okay
this is coming into a fractal core
of this shelf
so this is a shell
but it itself is a fractal core
it had you know it broke shelf here retested the apex and it did it yeah yeah it's a factor swing
explain that this is a factual swing and explain that this is inefficient and then when i break it down
it's this this and it's doing this so right now uh we had a relatively inefficient well actually quite
an inefficient pop into this apex here's the shell that's the shell price retested it not washed
there's a fractal core hair of this
of that high
there's a fractal swing that has a shelf
it's coming into that
is it going to respond
it's a vision or will it go to the top of it
or will it go to the top of the hair
and if it rolls over all of those levels
maybe it's because
this shelf is weak in the first place
on the higher time frame on the five
me you know
look at 10 of 5 you
would probably expect that high to get it
So maybe that's why these levels are talking about didn't work.
And what you will also notice then is when the levels are not going to work, they behave a certain way.
Price just doesn't respond when it should, you know, when the levels are going to work, they do respond.
So when this level is going to work, it will respond.
It will be very easy for you to trade.
When it doesn't work, it won't respond.
And when it's going to be that time that it runs out, none of these levels are going to work.
and you're going to see them get rolled over.
When you start seeing the characteristic of a run that's likely to extend and become inefficient,
you know, you might take a one loss here and the next level doesn't work in this watch.
This next level doesn't work in this squash.
That itself is giving you information about the new state.
It worked before.
What was that state?
It's not working now.
And I bet the times it does work, it won't be a run like this.
There will be a run like this.
Yeah.
You know?
Do you get it?
Yeah.
You will probably then spike into the level and then respond there, yeah?
So the run itself, how prices are moving into a level contextualize,
contextualize the levels, as detailed as you can be.
So here is a fractal core here of this shithful low price room.
That's inside of the 5 minutes or the H1 show, 5 inch oh.
Price is running more inefficiently, no rate of midflow.
This could happen and that could happen, doesn't matter.
Just observe it and explain.
Yeah.
And hopefully that will raise some questions.